<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="5"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[The
                                                   HoneyDo Boys, LLC
                         FREQUENTLY ASKED QUESTIONS
                                           two-forty-seven east thirty-third street - suite 1c
                                                     new york, new york 10016
                                                p:(917) 656-1235  • e:pturzio@gmail.com

                                             REMEDIATION SERVICES
                                                                 ®
                              Distributor for RatMats -SALES and SUPPORT

       Simple.                                                                      Ahh, who

         Safe.                                                                     asked ya?

      Secure!                                                        Easy to


                                                                       Install

                                                                         too!]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[The
                                                   HoneyDo Boys, LLC
                                           two-forty-seven east thirty-third street - suite 1c
                                                     new york, new york 10016
                                                p:(917) 656-1235  • e:pturzio@gmail.com

                                        FREQUENTLY ASKED QUESTIONS
                                                                 ®
                              Distributor for RatMats -SALES and SUPPORT
            1. Can it be used outdoors? Yes, it remains functional   4. Is it dangerous to use?   e RatMat is safe for
            and safe whilst being used outdoors.  e tiles are fully   humans.  e shock is highly unpleasant but is 40
            drained so water does not pool on the surface. Rats   times less powerful than electric fence in a farmer's
            and mice are still repelled even when the surface is    eld; these have been used safely for decades.
            wet. A human won't get a shock from water on the      5. How powerful is the shock?   e shock is
             oor in contact with the tiles, however it is advisable   pulsed at 1 per second (1Hz).  is is the maximum
            to wear shoes and avoid contact.
                                                                  frequency allowed by law.  e pulse is 5,000 volts
            If the tiles are submerged they will cease to function.  but very low amperage to make it safe. It is <0.1%
             e RatMat is made from PVC and stainless steel        as powerful as a de brillator.
            which we expect to last for decades, even in harsh
            weather conditions.                                   6. Can I drive a vehicle over it? A forklift as driven
                                                                  over the RatMat in a busy warehouse well in excess
            2. Does it kill the rodents? No, it does not kill or   of 150,000 times and it is still going strong. We have
            harm them.  e system is humane; it is not necessary   also had a fully laden  re truck drive over these:
            to kill rodents in order to protect an area.
                                                                  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=os0c1nlSZus
            By acting like an electric fence it is a completely    e tiles are made of hard-wearing stainless steel
            e ective barrier. Live rodents will leave the area,   and PVC, both materials used in high quality
            dead ones will have to be removed, increasing service   long-lasting  ooring surfaces and tiles.  e system
            requirements and costs. RatMat is a low-cost, low     needs to be mounted on a hard, level surface or the
            maintenance system over years of use.
                                                                  tiles will  ex and break.
            3. Can you make one that kills them? No, it requires
            far more electricity to kill a rat than a human. It also
            needs a sustained shock of more than a minute so if
            it was dangerous for rats it would be extremely
            dangerous for humans. Dead rats have to removed
            or otherwise present a bio hazard.

                                       e RatMat is extremely e ective
                                      without having to kill the rodents.]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[7. Can the tiles be cleaned? Yes, the tiles can be    12. How do I know if the tiles are working?
            vacuumed, swept, pressure washed and hosed down.      Having assembled the system and switching it on,
            Switch the energiser o  if washing with water.        there is no reason to expect that it wouldn’t be
                                                                  working. To be sure that electric pulses are reaching all
            8. Can the energiser run o  grid? Yes, we have an     areas of the surface an electric fence tester can be used.
            option for a battery powered energizer.
                                                                   ese measure up to several thousands of volts.13.
            9. Will the tiles work if covered in debris or snow?  13. Do the tiles need to be screwed to  oor or mat
            Keep the tiles clear of debris and snow in order to   operated as a moving structure? We recommend that
            be sure of full e ectiveness. However, they may well   the tiles are screwed to the  oor in any area where there
            be e ective even when covered. We have found that     is frequent footfall or tra c.  is prevents movement
            rodents often don’t walk on the device and will avoid   which could otherwise result in an area being exposed
            it completely, even having never had a shock o  it.
                                                                  to rodent damage.
             is has led us to the conclusion that they are able to  Each tile has two screw points. Alternatively, if the
            sense the electric  eld around the system, and may    mats are used in an area where they are unlikely to
            deter them even if the tiles are covered in debris.
                                                                  be moved during use, they can be left unscrewed so
            Clear debris in order to avoid arcing on the surface of  they can be lifted for access or to avoid damage if
            the mat. If there are concerns about snow build-up on   they are to be driven over on an uneven surface.
            the surface, under oor heating tiles can be placed
            under the system.                                     14. How much electricity do the RatMat’s use?
                                                                  0.45 watts; much less than an energy saving light
            10. Do I need a full mat or will a perimeter o er     bulb.  is is <0.1% of the energy of a de brillator,
            enough protection?  e more surface under and          0.45 joules, 40 times less powerful than a standard
            around an area to be protected covered with RatMat,   electric fence in a farmer’s  eld. It delivers a 0.003
            the better the level of protection. We recommend a    seconds (3 millisecond) duration pulse.
            perimeter for use around a car to be extremely e ective
            at stopping rodent damage completely.

            11. Will tiles work when they are switched o ?
            Rodents are neophobic, meaning that they are
            repelled by new objects, situations and smells.  is
            is how many less e ective rodent repellents work.
             e rodents may be wary of walking on the tiles
            when they are switched o  but if they are hungry or
            thirsty this is unlikely to deter them for long.
            We found when the  ooring was activated rodents
            often would not set foot on the tiles at all, only to
            walk straight across as soon as they were deactivated  Extra tiles can
                                                              always be added later.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[15. Do rodents get used to the RatMat shock?              KEY SELLING POINTS OF RATMAT
             e RatMat works like an electric fence.  ere is no    • Highly e ective at stopping all rodent incursion.
            evidence that animals become accustomed to pulsed     Testing shows they are able to detect the electric
            electric shocks which is why these fences remain      pulse and very rarely touch mat.
            e ective in farmer's  elds for decades. We have had
            no occurrences of rodents becoming accustomed to      • Can be used in situations where rodenticides can’t
            the shock; in fact they usually avoid it all together.  be used.  Eg, plentiful food supplies mean rodents
                                                                  don’t take bait. Use where rodenticides can’t be
            16. Do rats  jump over  the perimeter? Rodents        used eg food production, organic shops.
            don’t jump over the perimeter; our customers  nd
            it completely e ective at keeping rats and mice out.   • Long lasting. Each tile is very durable and built to
                                                                  last. A high initial outlay is likely to be very cost
            We  nd that they usually don't step on it at all when  e ective over life of tile.
            it is on, leading us to believe that they can sense the
            electric  eld around it. If this is the case they will be   • Traditional pest control methods aim to catch or
            able to sense the front edge but not the back edge of   kill the rodents; despite using this method for
            the  eld, so they won’t know where it ends and so     decades the rodent problem is worsening.
            don't jump into it.                                   If rodents in an area are killed those in an adjacent
             ere is evidence that rodents use the earths magnetic  area will move into it. RatMat denies entry, in
             eld to navigate so it is likely that the high voltage   order to protect property or equipment.
            pulses from the RatMat interfere with this, leading   • Ratmat is Eco Friendly, energy e cient and not
            to the rodents avoiding the area.
                                                                  dangerous to non target species, unlike rodenticides
                             MAIN USES                            and glueboards.
            • Protects rodent entrance points in a food factories.

            • Acts as a barrier across doorways at supermarkets.
            • Protects busy distribution warehouse entrances.
            https://www.abatepestmanagement.co.uk/rat-
            mat-installation-in-distribution-warehouse/

            • Protects entrances to high end sports cars storage –
            both inside and outside garage.

            • Use for warehouse quarantine with pest problems.
            • Grain storage protection.
            • Protect rodent damage to farm equipment.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[571.5 cm (225”)


           31cm
          12 13/64”
























       571.5 cm (225”)


























                                                                                       Each square is 1 RatMat Tile
                                                                                                12 13/64”
                                                                                         without corner or edge.]]></page></pages></Search>